Voila.
好了
Perfect!
完美啊！
What?
欸？
It's hot! Whoa!
好燙！哇！
Oh no.
糟糕
What? What are you doing, Mai?
怎麼了？舞，妳在幹嘛？
Well,
那個嘛
I thought I should make breakfast once in a while.
我想我偶爾也該做一次早餐
That thought is more than enough.
有那個想法就很夠了
I have a request. Please don't come near this kitchen.
爸爸有個請求，請妳不要靠近廚房
Seriously.
真是的
I don't think you got your mom's cooking genes.
我想妳沒有遺傳到妳媽媽的廚藝基因
You couldn't cook anything when you first started too.
爸一開始不也什麼都不會煮嗎？
I really didn't like your messy omelet.
我很不喜歡爸的髒髒煎蛋捲
Stop complaining. What did you expect?
別抱怨，妳期望什麼？
I never cooked while your mom was alive.
妳媽還在世的時候，我從不下廚
I never entered the kitchen.
我從沒進過廚房
Can you make Mom's croquettes?
你會做媽媽的炸丸子嗎？
-The ones with the soft potatoes. -Oh, them.
-有香軟馬鈴薯那種 -那種啊
-I love them. -Yeah.
-我喜歡吃 -對
By the way, you're 26 already but you're still making requests.
對了，妳都26歲了 卻還是只會提出要求
That's why you can't get married.
難怪妳嫁不出去
You're that one that banned me from the kitchen.
是爸不准我進廚房的
Look at the time.
不知不覺都這麼晚了
I'll make you breakfast.
爸爸幫妳做早餐
-Thanks. -Hurry up.
-謝謝！ -趕快！
Okay.
好
Mackerel?
鯖魚？
I really lack femininity.
我真是缺乏女人味
I should at least learn how to make a simple breakfast.
我至少該學會做簡單的早餐
EGGS BENEDICT
（班迪克蛋）
This looks so good.
看起來好好吃喔
Hollan… day…
荷蘭…日？
It's Hollandaise sauce.
是荷蘭醬
Eggs Benedict is so good.
班迪克蛋超好吃
-Which restaurant is it? -It's not a place.
-那是哪間餐廳？ -哪裡都不是
I'm going to make it.
是我自己要做
I'm rotting away
我正在腐化
because I'm always eating out with a middle-aged man like this.
因為我總是跟這樣的 中年男子一起出去用餐
You can cook, despite how you look?
妳這副樣子也能做菜？
I wish that was the case.
會做菜就好了
I thought so.
我就知道
But your dad is such a good cook.
不過，妳爸是很棒的廚師
That ultimate turnip was incredible.
那道究極蕪菁真是無與倫比
I'd like to try that.
我想吃吃看
General Manager Shindo.
真藤常務…
May we sit here?
我可以坐在這裡嗎？
-Sure. -Put that away.
-咦？是 -把那個拿開
General Manager Shindo,
真藤常務
you also use the employee cafeteria?
也來員工餐廳用餐嗎？
Of course, it's part of my job to understand the feelings
當然，了解員工的感覺
of the employees.
也是我工作的一部分
That's wonderful, Mr. Shindo.
那太好了，真藤常務
I hear you guys are a great pair.
聽說你們兩個配合得很好
I wouldn't say that we're a good pair--
我是不會說我們配合得很好…
-Ow… -Don't say unnecessary things.
-好痛… -多餘的話少說
The Branch Managing Department was wise to
分行管理部放一位女性在稽核班
place a female in Branch Inspection.
是很聰明的做法
There's a rise in female Branch Managers these days,
最近女性分行經理有增加的趨勢
so banks might be entering the age of female dominance.
銀行可能要進入女性主導期了
-Kodama. -Yes.
-兒玉 -是
I see, female dominance…
我知道了，女性主導…
I will work even harder.
我會更加努力的
-Enjoy your meal. -Yes, sir.
-吃飯吧 -是
-You've got a great appetite. -Uh… thank you.
-妳胃口很好啊 -嗯，謝謝
I lost my appetite,
我都沒胃口了
with Mr. Shindo sitting right in front of us.
真藤常務就坐在我們對面
But he's probably not as scary as the rumors make him out to be.
不過，他可能沒有傳言說的那麼可怕
He's supportive of working women too.
他也支持職場女性
His talk about female dominance must mean he expects a lot from me.
他提起女性主導 一定是他對我期望很高
-Whoa. -You're so clueless.
-哇！ -妳還真是無知
About what?
我哪裡無知了？
What I mean is, one word from him
我的意思是他一句話
and he can ship us off anywhere.
就能送我們去任何地方
I see. Please be careful, Mr. Soma.
懂了，相馬先生，請小心啊
-I said "us"! -That's right, Soma.
-我說的是“我們” -沒錯，相馬
-Please be careful. -Mr. Shibasaki.
-請小心啊 -芝崎次長
You forgot to stamp your name on this report.
這份報告你忘記蓋章了
-I'm sorry. -Please be careful.
-抱歉 -請小心
-As for you, Hanasaki… -What?
-至於花咲妳 -啊？
Your physical examination.
妳的健康檢查
-You got a reminder. -I'm sorry.
-妳收到催繳單 -對不起
The age of female dominance is near, but your time seems far off.
女性主導的時代快到了 不過，妳的時代似乎很遙遠
You two are such a great pair.
你們兩個還配合得真好
Did you come here to give us this?
你來就是要給我們這個的？
Oh! I forgot the main reason.
對，我忘記主要原因了
Please go to the West Yokohama Branch.
請你們去西橫濱分行
What is it this time?
這次是什麼事？
A young bank employee disappeared.
事實上，一位年輕櫃員工失蹤了
Disappeared?
失蹤？
A disappearance, huh…
失蹤啊
I wonder what happened.
我想知道發生了什麼事
Oh, it's hot.
好燙！
Mr. Soma.
相馬先生
The disappearance of a new employee is a story we hear
一位年輕員工失蹤
once in a while at a bank.
是我們在銀行偶爾會聽到的故事
-Really? -Yeah.
-真的啊？ -對
And when they open up a drawer inside their dormitory,
他們在宿舍裡打開一個抽屜時
there are piles of unprocessed documents. We hear stories like that.
裡面放著成堆未處理的文件 我們聽過那一類的故事
Wow.
哇
I'm sure it's just a new employee
我相信只是一位新員工
who couldn't handle the pressure and the workload.
無法處理壓力和工作負荷
We'll be done after asking some simple questions.
問完幾個簡單問題，我們就做完了
Disappearance, huh.
失蹤啊…
A job at a bank is tough, so it can be dangerous…
銀行的工作很困難
-Suppressing all that stress. -Yeah.
-壓抑所有壓力很危險 -對
I should be careful too.
我也應該小心
You have nothing to worry about.
妳沒什麼好擔心的
You don't suppress anything.
妳才不會壓抑任何事
-What? -Nothing.
-什麼？ -沒事
Nothing at all.
什麼事都沒有
WEST YOKOHAMA BRANCH
（西橫濱分行）
-Yes? -They're here.
-是 -他們到了
Excuse me.
打擾
I'm sorry for calling over the Branch Inspection
抱歉，為了這種麻煩
for this kind of trouble.
把稽核班找來
The employee
那位失蹤的員工
that's gone missing is this person named Hisashi Mitsuoka.
是這個叫做光岡久志的人
It's been a year since he was assigned to the Finance Department.
他被分派到融資課一年了
He was a diligent worker,
他工作勤奮
and we didn't notice anything different with him.
我們也沒注意到任何異樣
But he's been missing ever since he left home yesterday morning.
不過，昨天早上他離家之後就不見了
You haven't been able to contact him?
你聯絡不上他？
There has been no contact from him either to his house or to the bank.
家裡和銀行他都沒有聯絡
But according to his mother,
不過，他母親說
some of his clothes were missing from his house.
家裡少了幾件他的衣服
Then he probably wasn't involved in an accident.
那麼，他大概不是捲入意外事故
Give me a break. Why would he disappear on us?
饒了我吧，他為什麼這樣失蹤？
Do you have any idea why he disappeared?
請問妳對他失蹤的原因 有任何想法嗎？
-No. -How many companies was he in charge of?
-沒有 -他負責幾間公司？
Not very many. About 20 or so.
不多，二十個左右
-That's not a lot. -I see.
-不算多 -我懂了
But out of all the work within the branch,
不過，分行的所有業務當中
loans are the most complicated and difficult.
貸款是最複雜又最困難的
Well, there are no easy jobs.
沒有工作是輕鬆的
That's how all of us were trained.
我們所有人都是這樣訓練過來的
-Right, Mr. Soma? -Ah… yes.
-是吧，相馬先生？ -對，是
We are all in agreement that
我們都同意
he lacked the qualities necessary for a banker.
他欠缺銀行職員必要的素質
In addition to that, he was dealing with another problem.
除此之外，他還要應付另一個問題
Another?
另外的問題？
It's embarrassing to say this,
這還真難啟齒
but Mitsuoka's mother was the problem.
其實問題在光岡的母親
What kind of a problem?
是怎樣的問題？
It's what people usually call Monster Parents.
就是一般人所謂的怪獸父母
-Monster parent? -Even when he's a working adult?
-怪獸父母？ -即使他是出來工作的成年人了？
His mother calls in for him
他生病了
when he has a cold.
他母親幫他打電話過來
He should be the one contacting us, right?
應該是他聯絡我們，對吧？
That mother can't let go of him.
他的母親放不下他
Can't anyone take a firm stand against
就沒有人能採取堅定的立場
such an overprotective mom?
對抗如此過度保護的母親嗎？
Ow…
哎喲！
We would have if we could.
要是可以，我們就做了
The Mitsuoka family is very wealthy, and when he started working here,
光岡家裡非常有錢 從他在這裡工作開始
his mother transferred all of their accounts and investment trusts
他母親將他們所有帳戶、投資信託
to our bank from Hakusui Bank.
全部從白水銀行轉到我們這裡
But if you keep on worrying about their funds,
可是如果妳繼續擔心他們的資金
you will never have a say.
就永遠沒有發言權了
-How much do they-- -500 million yen.
-他們有多少… -五億日圓
500 million?
五億？
That is a valued client for sure.
那肯定是很有價值的客戶了
That's the reason why we can't talk back.
那就是我們為什麼不能反駁
-Not to that mother. -Where's the Branch Manager?
-那位母親的原因 -經理在哪裡？
It's the monster.
怪獸來了
Monster?
怪獸？
What will you do?
妳要怎麼辦？
It's your fault that my son is missing.
我兒子失蹤是你們的錯
Why isn't anyone looking for him?
為什麼沒有人去找他？
Hurry up and find my son!
快點去找我兒子
You cannot say that this is our fault…
妳不能說這是我們的錯…
Why would my Hisashi disappear?
我的久志為什麼會失蹤？
Something must have happened for
一定發生了什麼事情
a diligent and responsible person like him to run away!
才會讓像他這樣 勤奮負責的人突然出走
She's furious.
她氣炸了
She seems very strong.
她好像很強硬
But even so,
即便如此
Mitsuoka isn't the only one who's handling difficult work,
處理困難工作的人不是只有光岡一個
and we aren't expecting unreasonable things from him.
我們也不期望他做不理性的事
That's not acceptable.
我無法接受
I know that he was treated badly.
我知道他受到惡劣對待
Absolutely not…
絕對沒有
That is not the case.
事情不是那樣的
Let's calm down at once, Mother.
我們冷靜一次，媽媽
Mother? Don't you dare call me mother!
媽媽？你竟敢叫我媽媽？
-I'm not your mother! -True.
-我不是你媽！ -的確
-Hey. -Oh…
-喂！ -喔…
Who are those two?
這兩個是什麼人？
We came from headquarters regarding this case.
我們是從總部過來了解這個案子的
Headquarters. Great timing.
總部，來得正好
What are your thoughts on this?
你們對這件事有什麼想法？
My son has disappeared,
我兒子失蹤了
but people at this branch haven't done anything!
這個分行裡的人卻什麼也沒做
-Um… well… -You stay quiet.
-那個… -妳別說話
Was Hisashi saying anything before he disappeared?
請問久志在失蹤前有說過什麼嗎？
For example, was he having a hard time at work?
例如，他在工作上遇到困難
He was very patient, so he never voiced it,
他很能忍，從來不說出口
but it was painful to see him look so exhausted every day.
可是看他每天這麼疲憊，真的很痛苦
What do you call that thing for loans…
貸款的那個叫什麼？
-Proposal document? -Yes.
-提案書嗎？ -對
That was sent back to him again and again,
一次又一次退回給他
so he seemed to be having a very difficult time.
他似乎過得很痛苦
I see.
這樣啊
I know for a fact that he was being harassed.
我知道他肯定受到職權騷擾
He was not being harassed.
他絕對沒有受到職權騷擾
His proposal document was returned because his theory wasn't structured,
他提案被退是因為理論沒有條理
and it didn't meet the level of requirement.
沒有達到要求的水準
Then tell me,
那麼，妳告訴我
what is the level of requirement?
要求的水準是什麼？
Mrs. Mitsuoka, I understand that you're very worried.
光岡女士，我了解妳非常擔心
I also have a son.
我也有一個兒子
But I don't think a mother should interfere
但是，我認為兒子長大成人
with her grown son's workplace.
母親不應該去干涉他的工作
Are you trying to blame my son's disappearance on me?
妳是想把我兒子的失蹤 怪在我頭上嗎？
No, that is not what I meant.
我不是那個意思
It's all the bank's fault!
這全是銀行的錯！
There hasn't been a single apology at this stage in the game.
事情發生這麼久，連一句道歉都沒有
It's unforgivable!
不可原諒！
Say something!
說話啊！
-With all due respect… -Hanasaki.
-恕我直言 -花咲
But I think that's wrong.
我認為妳說錯了
What's wrong?
哪裡錯了？
The person causing trouble to the customers and the workplace
給客戶和工作場所造成麻煩的人
is actually your son.
實際上是妳兒子
No matter what his reasons, leaving behind his
不論他有什麼理由 不顧自己的責任就失蹤
responsibilities and disappearing, is unacceptable not just as a banker
不只是身為銀行職員，還有
but as a grown, working adult.
身為成熟的職場成年人 都讓人無法接受
What are you saying?
妳在說什麼啊？
The problem is
問題在於
the bank's response to this.
銀行對這件事的反應
You don't understand it at all.
妳完全不了解
No, you're the one who doesn't understand.
不了解的人是妳
-What? -This is not kindergarten.
-什麼？ -這裡不是幼稚園
It's absurd for a parent to
父母闖進孩子工作的地方
barge into a child's workplace.
不是很荒謬嗎？
-Hanasaki. -Oh…
-花咲！ -啊！
Oops, I've done it…
糟糕，我又來了
Absurd?
荒謬嗎？
If that's the attitude you're taking, I've made up my mind.
如果那就是你們的態度，我決定了
I will remove all of our accounts.
我要取消我們所有的帳戶
-Um… -Huh?
-嗯 -啊？
Mrs. Mitsuoka, please wait a moment.
光岡女士，請等一下
-Mrs. Mitsuoka, please wait. -Open it.
-光岡女士，請留步 -開門
-Calm down-- -Open it!
-冷靜下來 -開門！
-What have you done? -I'm very sorry.
-妳做了什麼啊？ -非常抱歉
You got her so mad.
妳讓她氣成那樣
What will you do if Mitsuoka's mother really removes all of her funds.
如果光岡的母親真的將所有資金撤走 妳要怎麼辦？
What did you come here for?
妳來這裡的目的是什麼？
You're hopeless.
妳無藥可救了
I'm sorry.
對不起
But she's horrible to think that having 500 million in funds
可是她太可惡，以為有五億資金
would let her get her way.
她就能予取予求
No amount of common sense will get through to that mother
再多顯而易見的道理也無法傳達給
who's lacking in common sense.
那個不講道理的母親
I don't think there's foul play involved, so we'll just
我不認為這當中涉及違規行為
write a report and finish this.
我們就寫份報告作結吧
I wonder what will happen to Mr. Mitsuoka?
不知道光岡先生會怎麼樣？
He abandoned his job and disappeared without any notice.
他丟下工作，不聲不響就消失
Even if he returns, it'll be too awkward to stay
就算他回來，留下來也會太尷尬
so he'll probably end up quitting.
他大概最後會辭職吧
-Right. -Um…
-也是 -那個…
You're investigating Mr. Mitsuoka, right?
你們在調查光岡先生嗎？
Yes.
是
I'm sorry to interrupt. My name is Okazaki, and I'm a teller.
抱歉打擾了，我叫岡崎，是個櫃員
Did you have something to tell us?
妳有話要對我們說？
I'm sure the Branch Manager had lots
我知道經理
of negative things to say about Mr. Mitsuoka.
說了光岡先生很多負面的事
-Well… -Mr. Mitsuoka…
-那… -光岡先生
He is not an irresponsible person.
不是不負責任的人
He was trying very hard to get a loan approved
他非常努力要幫一個客戶
for his customer.
通過貸款
-Redo it. -Yes.
-重做 -是
Redo it.
重做
His proposal document was turned back so many times.
他的提案書被退好多次
Goodbye.
辛苦了
But he would redo it each time.
但是他每次都重做
He was working very hard.
他工作非常認真
It's very different from what the Branch Manager was saying.
這和經理說的很不一樣
As for his mother, Mr. Mitsuoka was having the hardest time with her.
至於他母親 光岡先生和她相處最困難
-Really? -Yes.
-真的嗎？ -真的
I'm always telling my mom
我一直跟我媽說
to stop interfering with my work.
不要再干涉我的工作
But she won't listen…
但是她不聽
But I understand her too.
不過，我也了解她
She gave her all to raise me,
她付出一切養育我
and I became her purpose in life.
我成了她的人生目標
But because of his mother,
但是，因為他的母親
his boss and colleagues gave him the cold shoulder.
他的上司和同事都刻意冷落他
I see.
原來是這樣
Um… Will Mr. Mitsuoka get fired?
那個…光岡先生會被開除嗎？
Hm… we don't know.
我們不知道
Please help Mr. Mitsuoka.
請幫忙光岡先生
Ms. Okazaki…
岡崎小姐
Sorry for taking your time.
抱歉耽誤你們時間
Mr. Mitsuoka's image is starting to change.
光岡先生的形象開始改變了
Yeah, I thought he was just a mama's boy until now.
對，之前我一直以為他是媽寶
Let's investigate
我們去調查
how he was working.
他的工作狀況吧
Yes.
是
Here.
來
These are the loan related files that Mitsuoka was in charge of.
這些是光岡先生負責的貸款檔案
I see.
了解
What do you plan to do with all of this?
這些東西你們打算做什麼？
We need this to write our reports.
寫報告用的
I'm sorry, but our boss is very picky.
不好意思，我們老闆很吹毛求疵
I guess that can't be helped.
我想那是沒辦法的事
Thank you for your cooperation.
感謝您的配合
But please make it quick.
但是，請快一點
I don't want the Branch Manager to find out.
我不希望經理發現
-Yes. -Thank you.
-是 -謝謝
All right.
很好
We can find out how he worked by looking at
看他寫的提案書
the proposal documents.
就能知道他的工作狀況
Is that how it is?
事情是那樣嗎？
It's not easy to provide loans to a company, huh?
貸款給公司不容易吧？
Yeah. The way a proposal document is created
沒錯，提案書怎麼寫
affects whether it gets approved or not.
會影響是否能通過
That's where a banker can showcase his abilities.
這是融資課職員展現能力的地方
I see.
這樣啊
And how were Mr. Mitsuoka's proposal documents?
那麼，光岡先生的提案寫得如何？
Well…
這個嘛…
Are they problematic?
有問題嗎？
-They're not bad. -What?
-寫得不錯 -什麼？
Not only are they not bad, his proposal documents are pretty good.
不只是不錯，甚至是相當好
Judging by what I've read,
根據我看到的判斷
I think Mitsuoka was a decent guy.
我認為光岡是正直的人
-Really? -Yeah.
-是這樣嗎？ -是
This is what he was working on right before he disappeared.
這是他失蹤前正在處理的
-Omi Kikai Kougyou? -Yeah.
-尾見機械工業？ -對
It's engine parts.
是生產引擎零件的
One hundred million yen working capital.
一億日圓的營運資金
All the other ones have been approved,
其他案子她都讓它們通過
but this is the only one she didn't approve.
唯獨這一件不通過
DENIED
（駁回）
You're right.
你說得對
Mitsuoka rewrote it many times.
光岡重寫了非常多次
I've never met him,
我不認識他
so he may be the hopeless,
他可能是人人口中的
pampered kid that everyone says he is.
無可救藥嬌生慣養的媽寶
But I can tell that he was earnestly trying to
但是我看得出來
help out this company.
他非常想幫這間公司
Yeah.
原來如此
In the end, the loan did not get approved.
到最後，貸款沒有通過
The Branch Manager makes the final decision,
做出最後決定的是分行經理
but I wonder if he disappeared because
不過，我在想他的失蹤
he felt a sense of responsibility.
是不是因為他覺得自己有責任
I see.
我懂了
Branch Manager.
經理
What are you doing?
你們在做什麼？
You guys didn't leave yet?
你們還沒有離開？
We were looking through Mr. Mitsuoka's proposal documents.
我們在看光岡先生的提案書
Your job here should be done by now.
你們在這裡的工作應該完成了
Please leave.
請離開
I have one question.
我想請教一個問題
Why didn't you
妳為什麼
approve this loan?
不通過這個貸款？
Why do I have to answer that?
我為什麼要回答這個問題？
Does Branch Inspection have the right to
稽核班有權利
question our credit analysis?
質疑我們的信用分析嗎？
No, I was just curious because looking at the proposal,
不是，我只是好奇
it seemed to qualify for an approval.
因為從提案書看，似乎有資格通過
True, their sales are in the black,
沒錯，他們的銷售額是獲利的
but this company has a history
但是這家公司有不良紀錄
of ending up in deficit when surplus was expected.
預期有盈餘，最終卻出現虧損
Three years ago, right?
是三年前吧？
But they've recovered their performance recently,
不過，他們最近已經恢復績效
so they seem to be trustworthy.
似乎值得信賴
I will decide whether they can be trusted or not.
我會決定他們是否值得信賴
If by any chance, the loan for this company becomes unrecoverable,
萬一給這家公司的貸款無法回收
I have to take responsibility as a Branch Manager.
我身為分行經理必須負起責任
You have no right to tell me what to do.
你沒有權利告訴我該怎麼做
I apologize.
我道歉
May I ask one more question?
我可以再問一個問題嗎？
What is it?
什麼問題？
What did Mr. Mitsuoka say regarding
對於妳駁回的理由
your reason for denial?
光岡先生怎麼說？
His opinion?
他的意見？
How would I know?
我怎麼會知道？
Does he even have his own opinion to begin with?
再說，他有過自己的意見嗎？
But that's…
但那是…
These issues will be handled by our branch.
這些問題我們分行會處理
Please take your leave.
請你們離開吧
Please contact the HR department right away so that
請立刻聯絡人事部
we can get his replacement.
我們好找接替他的人
But Mr. Mitsuoka
但是光岡先生
is still an employee.
仍然是我們的員工
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花咲居酒屋）
Disappearance is a serious matter.
失蹤很嚴重啊
But I'm starting to
不過我開始理解
understand why Mr. Mitsuoka would want to disappear.
光岡先生為什麼想消失了
His boss is not understanding, and his mom is a ridiculous monster.
他的老闆不體諒人 他的母親又很荒謬
When you think about it, he's an unfortunate guy.
仔細想想，他真不幸
Well first of all,
首先，他媽媽
it's wrong that his mother is using her funds as a tactic to get her way.
利用她的資金作為 達到目的的手段就是錯的
Doesn't she realize that she's the one driving her son
她沒有意識到就是她自己
into a corner?
把她兒子逼到絕境
But parents
但是，做父母的
can't help but want to walk ahead of their child
就是只想走在孩子前面
and pick up rocks on the road
幫孩子撿起路上的石頭
so that they won't trip and fall.
這樣孩子才不會絆倒
They know that their child
他們知道孩子
has to fall and experience pain in order to grow,
必須跌倒，體驗過疼痛才能成長
but they can't help but feel helpless.
但是他們沒辦法，只是感覺無助
It's hard to explain a parents' love for their children.
很難解釋父母對子女的愛
That's why I think every parent has
所以我才認為所有父母
potential to become a monster parent.
都有成為怪獸父母的潛力
Good evening.
晚安
Good evening. Is it raining?
歡迎光臨，在下雨嗎？
Yes, it's starting to rain.
對，剛開始下
No.
不行
Why?
為什麼？
I rewrote it just as you instructed.
我都按照妳說的重寫了
Oh jeez,
可是呢
I thought you'd turn in something more acceptable,
我以為你會交出讓人更能接受的東西
but my fault for expecting something from you.
不過，對你有期待是我的錯
We waited all this time only to get denied?
我們等了這麼久 就只得到拒絕貸款嗎？
I'm
我真的…
very sorry.
非常抱歉
I'm very sorry.
我非常抱歉
I'm very sorry, everyone.
各位，我非常抱歉
-Mr. Soma. -Yeah?
-相馬先生 -嗯？
Do you want to look for Mr. Mitsuoka tomorrow?
你明天想去找光岡先生嗎？
What?
什麼？
I just can't let this go.
我沒辦法忘了這件事
But how do you plan to look for him?
可是妳打算怎麼找他？
Yeah… that's a good question.
對，真是個好問題
We have no idea where he could be.
我們完全不知道他會去哪裡
By the way, what happened to Omi Kikai Kougyo afterwards.
對了，貸款失敗之後
-When the loan was denied? -Oh, I looked into it.
-尾見機械工業怎麼樣了？ -我查過了
They were somehow able to come up with the funds.
他們還是設法找到資金了
I see.
這樣啊
Why don't we go there tomorrow?
不如我們明天去看看
We might find out something from the President.
也許可以從他們社長那裡知道一些事
Okay, let's do that.
好，就這麼辦
Wow, you're so agreeable today.
哇，你今天這麼容易說動？
What happened? Usually, you would say,
發生什麼事了？通常你會說
"That's none of our business."
“那不關妳的事”
I'm wondering if there's a reason why Branch Manager
我在想，經理不通過貸款
didn't approve that loan.
是不是有什麼理由
What do you mean by that?
你這麼說是什麼意思？
For example, a personal grudge?
例如，私人恩怨
-Personal grudge? -It's an example.
-私人恩怨？ -只是舉例
Is it the instinct of a former Finance Department worker?
這是前融資課員工的直覺嗎？
Mr. Soma is getting fired up for the first time ever.
相馬先生有史以來第一次暴走
Are you making fun of me?
妳是在取笑我嗎？
Not at all.
絕對不是
It's going to be busy tomorrow.
明天會很忙的
OMI KIKAI KOUGYO
（尾見機械工業）
What does Tokyo Daiichi Bank want with us now this late in the game?
都到這個時候了 東京第一銀行找我們想幹嘛？
I'm sorry to bother you, Mr. Omi.
尾見先生，抱歉打擾了
We were about to go bankrupt because your bank
我們差點破產
denied our loan!
都是因為你們銀行拒絕貸款
I ran around to gather funds,
我四處籌集資金
begging local credit unions and friends' companies
去求本地信用合作社和朋友的公司
and somehow got it together.
才好不容易振作起來
We are very sorry about that.
這件事我們非常抱歉
Um… we haven't been able to get in contact
我們聯絡不上
with Mr. Mitsuoka who was in charge of your loan application.
負責你們貸款申請的光岡先生
I heard.
我聽說了
I'm worried.
我很擔心
Since he was a clumsy, yet sincere kid.
他是個不靈光卻很真誠的孩子
Of course, I can't forgive your bank.
當然，我不會原諒你們銀行
But he didn't do anything wrong.
不過，他沒有做錯任何事
Would you have any idea where he might be?
你知道他有可能在哪裡嗎？
No.
不知道
I see.
這樣啊
How was his attitude towards work?
他對工作的態度如何？
He was very passionate.
他很有熱情
Good morning.
早安！
He would come by often,
他經常順路過來
to learn more about our company.
了解更多關於我們公司的事
He's young,
他雖然很年輕
but I've never had a banker who worked
但是，我沒遇過像他這樣
as hard as he did.
工作那麼認真的櫃員
I see.
這樣啊
But I'm very angry with your Branch Manager.
但是，我非常氣你們的經理
She dragged the process out until the day
她故意拖延進度 直到我們需要貸款款項的那天
we needed the loan, only to deny us!
只為了拒絕我們
Are you serious?
咦？你這麼說是認真的嗎？
Yeah.
是
It's an overall decision based on your company's past performance.
這是根據你們公司 以往表現做出的總體決策
If we can't get a loan from you,
要是你們不貸款給我們
our company will go bankrupt!
我們公司就要破產了
I'm begging you.
我求妳！
Unfortunately, I won't be able to help you.
很可惜，我幫不了你們
Branch Manager!
經理！
We were treated horribly.
我們受到惡劣對待
Did you have any trouble with
你曾經和中村經理
Branch Manager Nakamura in the past?
有過節嗎？
No. I've only exchanged greetings with her.
沒有，我只和她互相打招呼而已
President.
社長
You have a call from Central Machinery.
中央機械打來的，我要怎麼回答？
Tell them I'm not here.
說我不在
It's an official lawsuit now.
現在已經是正式訴訟了
We need to settle this in court.
問題要在法院解決
Did something happen?
發生什麼事嗎？
Oh…
喔
There's a company we're having problems with.
我們和一間公司有糾紛
So I took legal action. I really wish I didn't have to
我採取了法律行動
deal with a lawsuit
像這樣忙碌的時候
at a busy time like this.
我真的很不想打官司
We will take our leave now.
我們要離開了
We couldn't find anything about Mr. Mitsuoka's whereabouts
我們找不到光岡先生下落的任何訊息
or the connection with the Branch Manager.
或是和分行經理的關聯
But there's definitely something up with Branch Manager Nakamura.
但是，中村經理肯定有問題
Why do you think so?
你為什麼這麼想？
Banks teach that
銀行守則
"A loan denial should be determined quickly."
“拒絕貸款應迅速決定”
That way, the company can go search somewhere else for a loan.
那間公司才能去別處找貸款
-Okay. -But not Branch Manager Nakamura.
-對 -但是中村經理
She delayed the final decision until the day the loan was needed,
將最終決定拖延到 需要貸款款項的那天
and then she denied it.
然後她拒絕了
It's definitely strange.
這絕對不尋常
That means…
那就表示…
It's possible that
有可能是
she was purposely trying to cause this company to go bankrupt.
她想故意使這間公司破產
If that's true,
如果這是真的
that's unacceptable.
那就無法接受
Let's go back to headquarters and investigate Nakamura.
我們回總部調查中村
Yes.
是
Hello, this is Hanasaki.
喂？我是花咲
This is Okazaki from the West Yokohama Branch.
我是西橫濱分行的岡崎
What's the matter, Ms. Okazaki?
岡崎小姐，有什麼事嗎？
I just checked Mr. Mitsuoka's bank account.
我剛剛查了光岡先生的銀行帳戶
Then…
發現…
He withdrew money from the ATM at Honmoku Yamashita-cho.
他在本牧山下町的提款機領錢
When was that?
那是什麼時候的事？
10:40 a.m. today.
今天早上10點40分
He couldn't have gone far. Thank you, Ms. Okazaki.
他應該還沒走遠，岡崎小姐，謝謝妳
Mr. Soma, I'm going to go look for Mr. Mitsuoka.
相馬先生，我要去找光岡先生
Okay.
好
PRESIDENT JIN OMI
（尾見稔社長）
I guess I won't find any clues here.
我猜在這裡找不到線索
Oh, Kodama.
兒玉啊
I was looking for Mr. Shibasaki.
我在找芝崎先生
I guess he's not here… bye.
我猜他不在這裡，再見
Oh! Hold on a minute.
等一下
Hey, Kodama you used to
兒玉，你和西橫濱分行的
work with Branch Manager Nakamura from the West Yokohama Branch, right?
中村經理共事過，對吧？
-Yeah. -What kind of person is she?
-是啊 -她是怎樣的人？
Hm… well,
那個嘛
she's exactly how she seems. A capable female banker.
她和她給人的感覺一模一樣 是個能幹的銀行職員
-Anything else? -Something else…
-還有嗎？ -還有…
-I don't know. -Come on.
-我不知道 -拜託
Help your colleague for old time's sake.
看在過去的份上幫幫同事
Something about her friends, hobbies, or family.
關於她朋友、嗜好或家人的事
-Oh… -Ah! You just remembered something.
-啊 -你想起什麼了？
-But it's not that important… -That's okay.
-不過，不是很重要 -沒關係
She was in the company newsletter last year with her family.
去年她和她家人 有上公司的《社內報導》
Oh.
有了
Right here.
就是這個
MY FAMILY
（我的家族）
-Her son owns a company? -Yeah.
-她兒子在經營公司？ -對
It's the Branch Manager's proud son.
是分行經理引以為傲的兒子
What industry?
哪個產業？
It's a company that handles engine parts.
是處理引擎零件的公司
It's apparently doing well.
顯然做得很不錯
Engine parts? What's the company called?
引擎零件？公司名字叫什麼？
I don't know that.
我不知道
You don't know?
你不知道？
Is that my fault?
那是我的錯嗎？
Central Machinery?
中央機械？
You have a call from Central Machinery.
社長，中央機械打來的
What should I do?
我要怎麼回答？
Thank you, Kodama.
兒玉，謝啦
You were a big help.
你幫了大忙
I'll be heading back to Omi Kikai Kougyo.
我要再拜訪一次尾見機械工業
Hey, Soma.
喂，相馬！
What's Omi Kikai Kougyo?
尾見機械工業？
This man
這個人
withdrew money at the ATM here. Do you remember him?
剛剛在這個提款機領錢 你記得他嗎？
-I don't remember. -I see.
-不記得 -好的
Excuse me. Have you seen this man?
抱歉，妳見過這個人嗎？
No.
沒見過
No way!
不會吧？
Mr. Mitsuoka, please wait.
光岡先生，等一下！
Mr. Mitsuoka!
光岡先生！
Mr. Mitsuoka.
光岡先生
-Yes. -Oh, wrong person.
-有事嗎？ -認錯人了
I did it!
擊中了！
This is the best way to
這是消除沮喪的
relieve frustration.
最佳方式
Right, Mr. Mitsuoka?
對吧，光岡先生？
I'm Hanasaki from Branch Inspection.
我是分行稽核班的花咲
I'm glad you're okay.
很高興你沒事
Let's go back.
我們回去吧
Everyone at the bank is worried about you.
銀行的每個人都在擔心你
That's a lie.
騙人
But Ms. Okazaki…
不過，岡崎小姐
Ms. Okazaki is
岡崎小姐她
very worried for you, Mr. Matsuoka.
非常擔心光岡先生你
Oh, and…
還有
your mom too.
你媽
My mom didn't used to be like that.
我媽以前不是那樣的
But after she divorced my dad ten years ago,
可是，十年前她和我爸離婚後
I became her sole purpose in life.
我成了她活著唯一的目的
Then let's go apologize to the Branch Manager for your mom's sake too.
那麼，我們也去替你母親跟經理道歉
-I'll go with you. -I've already caused a lot of trouble.
-我會陪著你 -我和我媽
For the bank with my mother, and,
不僅對銀行造成很多麻煩
I was a no-call, no-show for a few days.
我還不聲不響曠職了幾天
Plus…
再加上
I wasn't able to get an important loan approved because of my inadequacy.
因為我的不適任 無法讓一個重要貸款案通過
I just wasn't meant to be a banker.
我不該成為銀行職員
That's not true.
才不是那樣
My boss was praising your proposal document saying that it was well-written.
我老闆稱讚你的提案寫得很好
Oh, and President Omi.
還有尾見社長
He said that no one had ever worked that hard for them before.
他說，從來沒有人為他們那麼努力過
There are people who appreciate your hard work, Mr. Mitsuoka.
光岡先生，有人欣賞你的努力
Plus, I don't think you're solely responsible
而且，我不認為
for the loan denial this time.
這次貸款不過的責任全在你
Branch Manager Nakamura
中村經理
is clearly hiding something.
很明顯有所隱瞞
What?
什麼？
I don't exactly know what that is yet.
我還不清楚確切原因
But if you continue running away,
但是，如果你繼續逃避
all the blame will be pinned on you.
所有責任都會推到你身上
Isn't that frustrating?
那不是讓人很沮喪嗎？
It's okay.
沒關係
I don't belong in the bank.
我不適合待在銀行
I never did, to begin with.
從來就不適合
I'm going to quit the bank.
我要辭掉銀行的工作
Is that what you really want? Don't you want to--
那個真的是你想要的嗎？ 你難道不想要…
Please leave me alone! I'm already
請不要管我！
finished anyway.
反正我已經完蛋了
You're not finished yet.
你還沒有完蛋
Nothing ever changes because you're always
什麼都不曾改變
running away like that.
因為你總是像那樣逃避
The same with your mother.
對你母親也是一樣
It's partly your fault that
你母親會變成那樣
your mom turned out that way.
有一部分是你的錯
Shouldn't you stop
你難道不應該
running away and face your problems?
正視問題，停止逃避嗎？
I'm sorry.
對不起
My mom died when I was ten.
我十歲時，媽媽就過世了
That's why I know that…
所以我知道
No matter how much they love their child,
無論父母多愛孩子
a parent will be leaving you first.
他們還是會比孩子先離開
But a child
但是孩子
must continue to live on their own.
必須靠自己活下去
Ms. Hanasaki.
花咲小姐
I won't run away anymore.
我再也不逃避了
Not from my mom,
不逃避我媽
or the bank.
還有銀行
MR. SOMA
（相馬先生來電）
This is Hanasaki.
喂？我是花咲
What?
什麼？
Mr. Mitsuoka.
光岡先生
-Hisashi. -Mother.
-久志 -媽
Branch Manager, Mitsuoka is…
經理，光岡他…
I'm very sorry.
我非常抱歉
What have you been doing?
你做了什麼？
You even brought your mom with you.
甚至帶你母親過來
Is it wrong for me to be here?
我來這裡有錯嗎？
My son didn't ask me to come with him.
我兒子並沒有要我跟他來
I came here of my own will.
是我自己想過來
This is an issue for the bank.
這對銀行造成困擾了
Can you please refrain from interfering?
可以請妳節制干預嗎？
Branch Manager, I'm not satisfied
經理，首先
with the way you handled this situation in the first place.
我並不滿意妳處理這件事的方式
Hisashi, you don't have to apologize.
久志，你沒必要道歉
Everything is their fault. So I'll--
都是他們的錯，媽媽會…
That's enough, Mother.
媽，夠了
Hisashi?
久志？
Please stop talking.
請別再說了
I'm in the wrong.
是我做錯了
So please leave.
請妳離開吧
I've caused everyone a lot of trouble because of my irresponsible actions.
我不負責任的行為造成大家很多困擾
I'm very sorry.
我非常抱歉
But
不過
I want to continue this job.
這份工作我想繼續做下去
Whoa. That's asking for too much.
喂，這個要求太過分了
You abandoned your work. You're disqualified as a banker.
你拋棄工作就是失職的櫃員
I agree with that.
這個我同意
For the last three days,
過去三天裡
I've been wondering what I'm doing.
我想知道我在做什麼
But still,
可是，我還是
I want to help society by working with loans.
想做貸款業務來貢獻社會
I want to help out small companies.
我想幫助小公司
Is that your conclusion?
那就是你的結論？
You're naïve.
太天真了
Do you think you can come back after all this?
你以為發生了這些事 你還能回來嗎？
Honestly, I don't want to see your face anymore.
坦白說，我再也不想看到你的臉
And of course, your mother's face too.
當然，還有你媽的臉
I'm very sorry about my mother.
我對我媽的事感到很抱歉
I will make sure that this will never happen again.
我絕不會讓這種事情再發生的
Again?
再發生？
It's really "like mother like son,"
還真是“有其母必有其子”
isn't it?
不是嗎？
You don't have a place here anymore.
這裡再也沒有你的位子了
Hurry up and write your resignation letter.
快去寫好辭職書
What?
什麼？
How else will you take responsibility?
你還能怎樣負起責任？
Hold on a second.
等一下
Mr. Mitsuoka is admitting his mistake and apologizing for it.
光岡先生已經承認錯誤，也道歉了
He still wants to come back and work here.
他還想回來這裡工作
He shouldn't have to quit.
他沒有必要辭職
This is our branch's problem.
這是我們分行的問題
-You have no right to interfere. -But--
-妳無權干涉 -可是…
He abandoned work and disappeared.
他丟下工作消失不見
All I can say is that Mr. Mitsuoka is clearly not suited
我能說的只有光岡先生
to be a banker.
不適合在銀行工作
With all due respect…
恕我直言
you are partly responsible for that, Branch Manager Nakamura.
中村經理，妳也要負一部分責任
I'm responsible?
我有責任？
That's ridiculous.
太可笑了
Then why did you prolong the loan process
那麼，妳為何要拖延
for Omi Kikai Kougyo,
尾見機械工業的貸款程序
only to deny it?
為的只是否決它？
A loan denial should be determined quickly.
拒絕貸款應該迅速決定
That's the iron-clad rule for loans,
這是貸款的鐵律吧？
am I right?
經理
That has nothing to do with this. First of all, they were
那和這件事無關，再說
trying to get a loan by using inaccurate sales estimates.
他們想要靠不正確的銷售數據估計 取得貸款
They're not a company we should be doing business with.
我們不應該和那種公司做生意
Is that really true?
妳說的是真的嗎？
Wasn't there another reason why you didn't approve that loan?
妳不通過那個貸款沒有別的原因嗎？
What are you saying?
妳在說什麼？
What do you mean by "another reason"?
妳說“別的原因”是什麼意思？
May I interrupt?
我可以打斷一下嗎？
What is it all of a sudden?
突然來是怎樣？
Excuse me.
抱歉
Branch Manager Nakamura.
中村經理
Do you know of a company called Central Machinery?
妳知道中央機械這家公司嗎？
It's the rival company of Omi Kikai Kougyo,
它是尾見機械工業的對手公司
who Mr. Mitsuoka was trying to secure a loan for.
光岡先生想幫尾見機械工業爭取貸款
You know, right?
妳知道的吧？
So what if I do?
我知道又怎樣？
Central Machinery was established in 2008.
中央機械成立於2008年
A location in Tokyo and Shinagawa. Capital stock is 30 million yen.
位在東京品川區，股本三千萬日圓
Representative
代表人是
is Mr. Yuji Nakamura.
中村雄治先生
Branch Manager Nakamura,
中村經理
it's your son, right?
他是妳兒子，對吧？
That has nothing to do with this.
那個與這件事無關
I'm here because it does.
我來這裡就是因為它有關
His company is being sued by Omi Kikai Kougyo
尾見機械工業正在控告他的公司
for violating
違反
the cylinder head patent, right?
汽缸頭專利，對吧？
Due to this lawsuit, the operation at your
妳兒子的公司因為這件訴訟案
son's company is at a standstill.
營運停頓
Because of your resentment,
妳因為憎恨
you not only prolonged the loan process for Omi Kikai Kougyo,
不僅延長尾見機械工業的貸款程序
but you denied them.
還拒絕貸款
To bankrupt them.
為的是讓他們破產
That's a false accusation.
那是不實指控
You don't have proof, right?
你沒有證據吧？
I made an objective decision
我做了客觀的決定
and denied the loan. That's all.
拒絕貸款，如此而已
It's true that there is no proof.
沒錯，是沒有證據
We'll have no way of knowing what was
我們無從得知
going through your mind.
妳心裡怎麼想
But you nitpicked on a loan proposal that should have
不過，妳對一個應該通過的 貸款提案吹毛求疵
been approved. That much is a fact.
那是事實
No matter how you deny it,
無論妳如何否認
this will really question your
妳身為分行經理的資格
qualifications as a Branch Manager.
都會受到質疑
Branch Manager, Nakamura.
中村經理
setting a company up for bankruptcy over a personal grudge
因為私人怨恨設計讓一個公司破產
is wrong.
是不對的
Do you really think that doing that
妳真的認為那麼做
will benefit your son?
會對妳兒子有好處嗎？
You said that
妳說過
Mr. Mitsuoka's mother was a monster,
光岡先生的母親是怪獸
but I will throw those words
不過，我要把那些話
right back at you.
還給妳
You are
妳才是
the true monster.
真正的怪獸
Who are you to tell me that?
妳憑什麼跟我說這些？
You don't have a child, so you won't understand.
妳沒有孩子，妳是不會懂的
What do you know about being a mother?
妳知道多少身為母親的滋味？
You're right,
妳說得對
I don't know…
我不知道
how you can love someone enough
怎樣才能夠愛一個人
to become a monster.
愛到變成怪獸
But
不過
I know this much for sure.
有一件事我很肯定
Loving your child doesn't give you the right
愛孩子並沒有賦予妳
to do whatever you want.
為所欲為的權利
What's wrong with that?
那有什麼錯？
I just wanted to…
我只是想要
help my son…
幫助我兒子
For my son…
為了我兒子
Hisashi.
久志
Mother,
媽
I'm sorry about earlier.
剛才的事我很抱歉
I'm going to work hard.
我會更加努力工作
I'm going to do all that I can
我會盡我一切能力
so that I can continue working at the bank.
讓我能繼續在銀行工作
I'll work hard so that you can feel at ease.
我會更努力工作讓媽媽安心
So can you believe in me,
您可以相信我
and see how I do?
等著看我的表現
Thank you very much.
非常感謝
Good luck.
加油
Let's go.
媽，我們走吧
I'll try it.
我吃吃看
Yeah.
好
How is it?
如何？
Hm…
嗯
Well…
那個嘛
It's so-so.
馬馬虎虎
-It's no good. -Of course. You just started.
-不好吃 -當然，妳才剛開始
It takes more than a day or two to master it.
想掌握好這個，不是一兩天能辦到的
Mom's omelet was so good.
媽媽的煎蛋捲好好吃
-It was sweet and fluffy. -Yeah.
-香甜蓬鬆 -對
-I still remember it.
-我還記得 -是啊
-Hey, Dad. -Yeah?
-爸 -嗯？
A mother's love
媽媽的愛
is really deep, isn't it?
非常深吧？
So much that it makes you blind.
深到讓人盲目
I want to become a mom like my mom.
我想成為我媽那樣的媽媽
What? You don't even have a husband yet.
說什麼啊？妳連丈夫都還沒有
-Oh, right. -Hm?
-對了 -嗯？
I think someone like Mr. Soma would be great.
爸爸認為相馬先生這樣的人很不錯
What?
什麼啊？
Mr. Soma is a great catch. He's single, right?
相馬先生是不錯的選擇 他不是單身嗎？
Plus, if he becomes your husband we can drink every night.
而且，要是他成了妳丈夫 我們可以每晚喝酒
You're already drinking with him all the time.
你已經老是和他一起喝酒了
Aren't dad's supposed to stop their daughters from getting married?
爸爸不是應該阻止女兒結婚嗎？
I can't wait.
我迫不及待
Brush up on your cooking skills in the meantime.
妳同時要提高妳的廚藝
It's not going to happen, okay?
那是不可能的，知道嗎？
-Let's have some salted squid. -Yeah.
-我們吃點鹹香小管 -好
Branch Manager Nakamura
中村經理
ended up getting a strong warning.
最後被記一個大警告
But she will most likely be demoted
不過，下一次輪調
during the next rotation.
她很可能會被降級
She mixed official business with
她在做決定時
personal affairs when making decisions.
將公事與私事混在一起
It seems like the responsibility of being a Branch Manager,
似乎分行經理的責任
was too heavy of a load for a female like Ms. Nakamura.
對於中村女士這樣的女性負擔太重
Yes, you're absolutely right Mr. Shindo.
是，真藤常務說得太對了
But I wonder how those people
可是，我很訝異那些稽核班的人
at Branch Inspection found out about
是怎麼發現
her son's company.
她兒子的公司呢？
Oh, I wonder…
這個啊…
I… I wonder how.
不知道呢
-Kodama. -Yes.
-兒玉 -是
You're sweating.
你在冒汗
Is it that hot in here?
這裡那麼熱嗎？
N… no.
沒…有
It's just the right temperature.
溫度剛剛好
I ended up drinking too much because of what Dad said.
因為爸說的話讓我喝多了
-Hey. -Oh… hey!
-喂 -喔
Morning.
早
Here you go.
給妳
Mai!
舞
Nope!
不！
Never!
絕對不會！
I'm imagining weird things thanks to Dad.
都是老爸害的，讓我想像奇怪的事
What are you saying? Your business card came in.
妳在說什麼啊？妳的名片來了
Oh… thank you. And good morning.
謝謝，還有早安
You're being so weird this early in the morning.
妳今天一早就怪怪的
Oh by the way,
對了
Mr. Mitsuoka is back at work, and doing very well.
岡光先生回去工作了，而且表現良好
That's great to hear. By the way…
那太好了，對了
It's love, right?
那是愛，對吧？
L… love…
愛…
Ms. Okazaki.
岡崎小姐啦
She has feelings for Mitsuoka, huh?
她對岡光有好感
This is why I don't like old men because
就是這樣，我才不喜歡老男人
they love gossiping.
老男人真愛講八卦
Who are you calling an old man?
妳叫誰老男人？
Oh, good morning.
喔，早安
But a chance meeting
不過，一次偶遇
might be hiding somewhere closer than you think.
可能正躲在比妳想得更近的地方
What? You were listening?
什麼？你在聽啊？
Yeah, of course.
是，當然
Spring is the season of love…
春天是愛的季節
Mr. Shibasaki and his wife started as an office romance.
芝崎先生和他太太 是從辦公室戀人開始的
This is going to be a long one.
他要講很久了
-I see. -As for me and my wife…
-了解 -至於我和我太太
Oh… I forgot!
啊，我忘了！
I have to go pick up some file folders.
我得去拿幾個檔案夾
Wait, I'm still--
等等，我還在…
-I'll be off. -Wait, Hanasaki.
-我走了 -等等，花咲
A special audit?
金融廳檢查？
We're here for inspection.
我們是來做檢查的
Aota went to the Nakano Branch?
青田去了中野分行？
Don't overlook anything. Be thorough.
不要漏看任何東西，要徹底檢查
An informer?
洩密者？
No way.
不可能
This is interesting.
這個有意思
It's wrong as a human being.
你做人失敗！
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita
字幕翻譯：李怡樸